"Previously on The Mentalist..."
- You really like this guy, huh?
- He got a promotion in D.C.
and he asked me to go with him
so we can be together.
My sister's Amy Welker.
You have to find her.
- She was abducted with you?
- Yes.
"How long were you held captive?"
"I couldn't tell.
I never saw the sunlight."
"Two days, maybe."
Her sister was there.
There are more girls.
- You're right-handed.
- Yes.
So, that heart on your hand,
y... you didn't draw that?
No. They did.
They took a sample of blood from all the
trafficking victims, including Daniela.
- Why do you think they needed the blood?
- I don't know yet.
Look, I... I've been thinking
about you leaving.
And I really want you
to be happy.
And that is the most important
thing to me...
That you do
what makes you happy.
The body's been cut open.
They're killing these girls
for their organs.
And I need a list of every
transplant facility in the country.
We need to track down
where these organs went.
Thanks, Wylie.
What's going on?
The office said multiple homicides?
Three, all women.
And we believe they were
from the same trafficking operation
that we investigated.
It gets worse.
All three girls were missing vital organs.
- What?
- They were harvested...
We think for sale on the black market.
How can I help?
You could start with this place...
Wheatondale Medical Center.
We need to know who had access to it.
And, also, the Qasimi brothers.
Well, you don't think they had anything
to do with this?
They worked closely
with whoever abducted these girls.
I'm guessing the same people
are behind their murders.
I'll contact Beaumont penitentiary.
I should be able
to see the Qasimis tonight.
Okay, if you guys have
any problems, give me a call.
Three women.
Think there were more?
Many more.
Covered up like they're old cars
just...
set there unceremoniously.
It's like you set down a cup of tea.
And look at their feet...
Their blood types written on their soles.
There's nothing special
about these murders.
It's just routine, transactional.
It's a business, a production line.
Exactly.
"Our bureau's major-crimes unit
covers the greater D.C. area."
"We investigate hundreds
of crimes each year"
"ranging from homicide
to armed robbery to kidnapping."
- Sounds like you've got your hands full.
- "We do."
"So when Pike told me you were thinking
of making a move to D.C."
"I jumped at the chance to snap you up
before someone else did."
"Job's yours if you want it."
Uh, that sounds great, sir.
I just need some time to think about it.
"Wouldn't have it any other way.
But do me a favor."
"Let me know as soon as you can."
- Thank you.
- "Thank you."
- "Pike, Abbott."
- Talk soon, Don.
Wow.
Sounds like a great gig, Teresa.
You know we'd be sorry to lose you.
So...
What are you thinking?
- I don't know yet.
- Well, Abbott's right. It's a great job.
- And Don's the best.
- I believe you.
Well, look, Teresa.
I've been patient.
I...
I kinda went out on a limb for you...
Pushed Don to pass on other candidates
so that I could have you with me in D.C.
I mean, I know it's a big decision
but it's a decision you need to make.
Morning, Lisbon.
Pike.
All right, got anything?
We might have a hit on the truck used to
traffic the girls to the Qasimi brothers.
It's the one we intercepted.
We've had that truck for days.
What's taking so long?
Well, the truck was leased by one company
which is owned by another company
which is a subsidiary of another company.
There's six in total, all privately owned.
Which makes figuring out
who owns it a nightmare.
I just got back from the prison.
- The Qasimi brothers are dead.
- What?
They were stabbed to death
in their cell this morning.
Whoever abducted these girls
must have gotten to them.
We think Amy is with a group of girls
that was trafficked
across the border into Mexico.
From there, she would've been
transported by cargo ship
most likely to a buyer in South America.
- South America?
- We estimate Amy will be arriving
at a foreign port
in the next few days.
That'll be our best chance to find her.
Why wasn't I with her?
Why was I held separately?
A small number of girls
were pulled from the main group.
You were one of them.
That's why you had the heart
drawn on your hand.
What happened to them?
They were taken
to an abandoned medical facility
outside Dallas.
We found the girls murdered.
Their organs had been harvested.
Oh, my God.
- Was... was Amy...
- No.
We're sure of that.
We're gonna find her.
What you doin'?
Nothing'. Thinking.
What, uh, meaning-of-life-type stuff?
Something like that, yeah.
I got something.
Wheatondale Medical Center.
I started background checks
on everyone associated with it.
- Anything turn up?
- No.
But then I cross-referenced
that list of names
with the trucking-company information.
Got a hit...
Michael Ridley.
- Who's he?
- A partner in the equity group
that sold Wheatondale two years ago
so he would've had access to the building.
And he just so happens to own
the same company
I traced our confiscated truck back to.
That is quite a coincidence.
Yes, it is.
So, you can understand
why we're here, Mr. Ridley.
Oh, I'll admit it's suspect
but I can assure you I had nothing to do
with these horrific acts.
What was your involvement
in the Wheatondale Medical Center?
It was a distressed property.
My partners and I purchased it
sold off the medical equipment
that was still valuable.
Just like harvesting a crop.
When was the last time you were there?
Wheatondale? I've never been there.
- Mr. Ridley, what was...
- Interesting office.
Very plain, simple.
No muss, no fuss.
Never felt the need to decorate.
An office is for work.
You were saying?
What were 30 abducted women doing
in a truck owned by your company?
One of my companies.
I'm in shipping and logistics.
- I own or co-own dozens.
- Let's talk about that.
Your corporate structure
is incredibly convoluted.
It's almost like you didn't want the truck
linked back to your company.
Not at all.
It's simply done that way
for tax purposes.
I wouldn't wanna bore you with the details.
What is so boring about the details?
Well, to me, nothing, but for most people
corporate accounting isn't exactly thrilling.
- We've got time.
- Unless, of course
there's something you're trying to hide.
I think we're getting off
on the wrong foot.
Here's the name and number
of my CFO.
He'll make sure you have access
to everything you need.
I have absolutely nothing to hide.
Hello, Mr. Ridley.
Anthony, I just had a conversation
with the FBI.
- I see. Is everything all right?
- No.
Apparently, they found three dead women
at the Wheatondale medical facility.
Well, that is disturbing.
Is there anything I can do to help?
I'm sure the FBI will find
whoever's responsible.
Nevertheless, I'd like you to look into it.
Absolutely, sir.
Anything you need.
- Hey, Cho.
- Hey.
You got a minute?
What's up?
I got offered a job in D.C.
You gonna take it?
I don't know. Maybe.
- Don't tell anybody, all right?
- Okay.
It'd be a great move, though.
- You think?
- Absolutely.
You remember the first day
we worked together?
- Sure.
- I almost quit.
- Really? Why?
- Rigsby.
But then I saw the way you worked.
I knew I had to stay.
I wouldn't be where I am today
if it weren't for you.
Whatever decision you make,
it's been an honor.
Thank you.
By the way, they're ordering
Chinese for lunch.
Forensics found something
at Wheatondale...
DNA from 16 different people, so far.
Wait. Are you saying that 16 women
were killed in there?
About 15 of them were women.
Some of the DNA came from a man.
His name's Alexander Lark.
At first, I thought
he might be another victim
but he was never reported missing.
Do you think he was involved?
I think that he's the one
that carved up these women.
Up until seven years ago,
Lark was a surgeon
and that's when he lost his license.
Well, where is he now?
The local P.D. went to Lark's house
but they didn't find anything.
His neighbors haven't seen him
in a couple of days.
Does he have any family in the Area?
He has a daughter, April.
She lives in San Antonio.
Okay. Well, grab Cho and see
what the daughter knows.
April, have you spoken
to your father recently?
Does two years ago count?
He's been missing for a few days.
We need to ask him some questions.
Like I said, we don't talk much.
- Why not?
- Do you have a couple hours?
Mom died, I don't know, eight years ago.
Dad decided that was a good time
to start drinking.
He became someone different...
Lost his job, his house.
I don't even know
how to be around him anymore.
Do you have any guesses
where he might have gone?
Anything could be useful.
It's probably nothing
but my father grew up near the beach
in Corpus Christi.
Sometimes, when he wanted
to get away, he'd go there.
Okay. Thanks for your time.
What kinda trouble is he in, anyway?
Actually, never mind.
I don't even wanna know.
Thank you for seeing us
again, Mr. Ridley.
Anything to help.
- Garish, I know. My ex-wife's idea.
- No.
It was your idea.
It's an intimidation technique.
- Is it?
- Yeah. You want whoever comes here
to know exactly who they're dealing with.
Well...
- now we know.
- Very perceptive.
So, how can I help you?
You recognize this man?
His name's Alexander Lark.
He was a doctor years ago.
No, can't say that I do.
- He's lying.
- Excuse me?
Lark worked with you. It's as plain
to me as that nose on your face.
I'm beginning to realize
you've got a certain idea about me
but let me be more than clear.
You are mistaken.
We're gonna find Lark,
and when we do
we'll know if you're involved.
"Cho, it's Wylie."
"Corpus Christi P.D. spotted Lark's car."
"It's in the Marina district."
There's his car.
Here we go.
Alexander Lark!
- FBI! Don't even think about running!
- Let me see your hands.
Just relax. Calm down.
"Hello, Anthony. What's the status?"
We have a problem.
The FBI is arresting Lark.
They cannot take him alive.
All right, let's go.
"Is Lark in range?"
Yes, but he's not alone.
Go. Go now.
- Everybody okay?
- Yeah, I think so.
You've had your drink.
Now tell us how Ridley's
operation worked.
Uh...
Ridley had a guy named Jesse.
His real name was James O'Conner.
He was found dead this week.
Uh, h... he'd find the girls for Ridley.
"Most of them were sold off"
"but if their tissue and blood type
were a match"
"for someone needing
an organ transplant"
"they were brought to me...
a heart drawn on their hand."
"And you killed them?"
"They came to me drugged."
But yes, yes.
Propofol.
They never felt a thing.
I'd remove the organ and one
of Ridley's employees would pick it up
"and deliver it to the buyer."
Ridley forged paperwork
so the organs seemed aboveboard.
The hospitals that performed
the transplants never had a clue.
This employee...
you have a name?
No. He wasn't a chatty type.
"He was, uh, young, maybe late 20s."
"I'd store the bodies in the freezer"
and every few weeks, that same guy
would come and take them away.
When did you start working for Ridley?
Uh... six years ago.
He was an old patient.
When I lost my license,
he offered me a job.
I needed the money, and he paid well.
You see, Ridley's been involved
with human trafficking for years.
He used the money he made
to go into legitimate business.
I'm curious.
Did it ever bother you...
killing these women?
Sure.
Of course.
But after a while...
you stop thinking about it.
And that means profits for the next quarter
are expected to rise by at least 7%.
- Yeah, I wouldn't be so sure of that
- Perhaps more.
especially when your CEO
is behind bars.
Michael Ridley, you're under arrest
for human trafficking and murder.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say or do can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
Ridley's not talking so we don't know
which ship the girls are on
but we believe
they're headed to South America.
"How many ships are we looking at?"
45 total, but 33 have docked
and been inspected.
Unfortunately, nothing was found.
The remaining 12 will be arriving
in your territories.
We need a search of each one.
"That's gonna be a problem on my end."
"Colombian port officials
are bought off by the cartels"
"and drugs are going in and out."
"They're not just gonna
open the doors for the FBI."
"Ambassador Moreno,
this is Agent Cho with the FBI."
Hello, agent. I was just briefed
on your situation.
I'd be happy to facilitate
a search warrant
"but it may take some time."
We don't have time, sir.
I'm sorry, but there's a chain
of procedure.
You understand what will happen
to these girls if we don't find them?
- "Agent Cho..."
- You understand what will happen to you?
- Are you threatening me?
- No, sir.
But I'm not an enemy
you wanna make.
Now, we know that the cartels
have infiltrated local government...
Even high-ranking officials like yourself.
"If this warrant doesn't come through
in time"
"we'll be forced to look into it."
Let me see what I can do.
Thank you, sir.
They're letting Ridley out on bail.
I'd say congratulations
but I think your victory will be short-lived.
- Give us a moment?
- Michael. I...
I know you want me punished.
You wanna see me suffer.
I wouldn't object to it.
You've misjudged me.
I've done nothing wrong.
- You truly believe that, don't you?
- Of course I do.
It's just business to you...
all these women dead.
It's just numbers on a spreadsheet
figures on your bottom line.
First of all, I didn't kill anyone.
But perhaps the man who did
wasn't solely concerned with money.
Perhaps he had a greater cause
in mind.
Perhaps the lives of these women
were taken
so that the lives of important men
could be spared...
Scientists, leaders, philanthropists
people who shape the world.
I... I'm not sure how
I'm supposed to react to that.
Oh, come on. It's just us.
If anyone could understand
that perspective, it's you.
Well, you're right. I've worked
with psychopaths and monsters for years
so, yes, I do understand
your perspective...
very well.
Have a lovely afternoon.
Sure.
You too.
We want names
of every organ recipient.
We find these people
we can get them to testify against Ridley.
I, I need another drink.
Not this time. Not until you talk.
I... I can't help you.
Ridley was the only one
who knew their names.
He kept the information
on an encrypted laptop.
I never had access to it.
And you never talked to Ridley
about any of these people?
Not once in six years?
Mr. Lark, you have the chance
to do something right for once.
Um...
Uh, well, it's not much, but...
Uh, last week
uh, I had a meeting at, uh,
Ridley's house.
"I got there early
and overheard Ridley with a client."
"He was sick, uh, said he needed
a transplant as soon as possible."
"I heard him say he was Nigerian"
"and in the States conducting meetings
for his oil business."
"H... h... he and Ridley had met
at a fundraiser in Houston."
"Okay. Anything else?"
"He had, uh, an expensive
gold watch..."
"A Philippe Badeaux."
I used to have one just like it.
Okay, so you don't have recipient names.
What about Ridley's employee?
You know, anything else
you can tell me about him?
What's this?
Ridley's employee had
that tattooed on his forearm.
Run it through the database.
See if anything pops.
You got it.
Jane.
Scooch over.
How often do you sleep
in your own bed, anyway?
Oh, I don't like that bed.
Too many lumps.
Maybe you should get a new bed.
Actually, you know what?
I always did like this couch.
Jane.
Jane...
Take your call, Lisbon.
Fischer?
What? When?
Guards found him this morning.
- Did he leave a note?
- No.
But they found that on his bed.
Now, what do you make of that?
Does this belong to you?
Where did you find this?
We found it in your father's cell.
But that's impossible.
I was wearing it last night.
I... I thought I lost it.
April...
Were you alone last night?
Yes.
Why?
Wait, a... are you telling me
that there was someone in my house?
Oh, my God.
Ridley found her.
That's why Lark killed himself.
And killed our case
against Ridley in the process.
Maybe so, but we can't prove it.
I'm having Wylie pull
the security tapes from the jail.
Maybe we can find out how Ridley
got the necklace into Lark's cell.
Good idea.
What about the man that worked for him?
We're looking into it but all we have
is a vague description and a tattoo.
- The Nigerian.
- Excuse me?
The man Lark spoke of.
The man Ridley met with.
If Lark was right and the man
was an organ recipient
he'd be able to implicate Ridley.
If he'll talk
and if he actually was a recipient.
We don't even know
if he's still in the country.
You don't have to be so negative.
You haven't found her?
No. Not yet.
She's alive.
I know she is.
We think we've narrowed down
her location
to one of four cargo ships
headed for Colombia.
If we're right
she should be arriving
within 12 hours
and we'll be there to find her.
And if you're wrong?
I got him.
Well not him, specifically
but I think I found the fundraising event
Lark was talking about.
The Blue Skies gala.
It was held six weeks ago in Houston.
Looks like it was
an environmental charity event
put on by domestic oil companies.
Including representatives
from Africa-based Ar Ahim Energy.
This must be the event
where Ridley met this Nigerian man.
Nice work.
E-mail me the contact info
for the event company.
Already did.
Hi. I'm Patrick Jane.
I'd like to see the evidence
from the abandoned hospital...
All of it, please.
So, these are all the pictures
from the Blue Skies gala?
Every last one according
to the event-planning company.
The Nigerian man is here somewhere.
You know, we can wait
for Jane if you want.
Why? He hates this kinda stuff.
I don't know.
You guys always work together.
Not always.
Here's a possibility.
Lark said the man wore
an expensive watch.
- Gold, right?
- That's him.
His name is Jonas Diop. You were right.
He's a Nigerian oil executive.
But according
to his recent credit-card activity
he's still in the Houston Area.
Do you know where he's staying?
Uh...
The Park Huntley hotel.
- Hello?
- "Mr. Diop, hello."
How are you?
You doing okay?
I hate to have to make this call
but the FBI may be looking for you.
You knew the risks
when you got involved.
If I were you, I'd leave
the country immediately.
- Lisbon?
- "I'm afraid I've got some bad news, Jane."
- "What's up?"
- Jonas Diop's gone.
His driver says he left
the Houston airport
on a private plane 20 minutes ago.
"He's headed back to Nigeria."
- Ridley.
- "He was our only lead."
I'm running out of ideas.
Well, I'm not.
- You have a plan?
- Yeah, but I'm gonna need your help.
Why don't I like the sound of that?
Well, I'm gonna need you
to be deceitful and corrupt
and you'll be breaking
numerous laws.
Lisbon?
- I'm thinking.
- Ridley will walk.
This is the only way.
Hey, hey, are you a medium or a small?
You're not helping yourself
out here, Jane.
Meet me at Wheatondale
in two hours.
Thank you.
- What is this?
- You'd guess scotch, wouldn't you?
Japanese whiskey...
25-year-old single malt.
One of my few indulgences.
It's delicious.
But that's just scotch.
- It's Speyside. I'm sure of it.
- Here.
I'll prove it to you.
Wow. Look at that.
I stand corrected.
You're not the first one
to make that mistake.
People assume it's not as good,
but they're wrong.
It's better, in fact.
Some say it's the water,
but I have my own theory.
I think it's cultural.
Japanese have it in their blood
to sacrifice everything
in order to succeed...
Like I do.
Like you do, I believe.
We tracked down one of your clients...
Jonas Diop.
Diop's a business associate,
not a client.
But I'm curious...
what did he have to say?
Nothing.
He fled the country
as soon as he heard we wanted
to talk to him.
How unfortunate.
Yeah, I know it was you
that tipped him off.
So far, you've been one step
ahead of me but, uh...
Well, sooner or later...
Oh, if you and the FBI were gonna
prove your case against me
you would've done so by now.
No, I think you've lost
the battle, my friend.
Best to concede defeat and move on.
I'm not sure that I can do that.
Something wrong?
I, uh...
I... I don't feel well.
I think it's time for you to leave.
Yeah, might be time.
Y... you don't look so good...
a little pale.
Shaky.
You look like you need to lie down.
It's almost as though
you've been... drugged.
You know, I've been thinking
about what you said, you know?
Some lives are more valuable
than others.
Anyway...
I figured, uh...
Well, I couldn't agree more.
Sorry you didn't catch it.
"Sayonara."
- All set?
- Yeah.
Jane, we don't have to do this.
We can still stop.
No, no. It's a little late
for that, isn't it?
- Is he restrained?
- Yes.
And the gag is securely
in his mouth?
- Yes, it is.
- Okay.
Don't worry. This won't hurt a bit.
He's a screamer.
Hold him.
- Lisbon, hold him still.
- I'm trying, Jane.
No!
He's not gonna last long.
That's all right. He isn't meant to.
Sponge.
Get it in there.
Oh my God!
He's gone.
He's awake.
You said he was gonna be
unconscious, Jane!
It doesn't matter what I said.
What's going on?
Where am I?
Quiet.
You killed him.
- You killed Anthony.
- I said, be quiet.
What are you gonna do to me?
I think you already know
the answer to that.
You're insane!
- Let me go now!
- Or else what?
You're a cop. You can't do this.
This is wrong.
Not after what you've done.
This is poetic justice.
What do you want, a confession?
You know it'll never hold up in court.
Eh, I think you might be right
about that.
Stop. Stop!
I'll tell you everything!
- I think it's a bit late for that.
- Just, would you, wait. Wait.
My laptop. I...
I kept records... of everyone.
We know about the laptop.
It's password-protected.
I'll tell you the passwords! Stop!
Stop. I'll tell you anything you want.
Just stop, please.
Please.
Tell it to me. What's the password?
I'm the last person
who can save you.
F79VR22.
All right?
We got it. We're done here.
Your agents tortured my client.
- He's lying.
- Jane.
There is no evidence
of physical abuse.
Psychological torture
is still torture, Agent Abbott.
My client was made to believe
that he'd be killed by Mr. Jane
making any evidence
you may have gathered inadmissible.
Yes, if that evidence is ruled
to have been gathered illegally.
Which it won't be.
My client has sworn
to these accusations.
Your client is a monster facing life
in prison for what he's done.
I'd say just about anything
if I were him.
You killed him.
Please, don't say anything.
He murdered a man that worked for me.
Anthony Tremmel.
- You're certain?
- I watched him die.
This is from a live security feed...
from our holding cells downstairs.
No...
It... it can't...
I saw him.
Perhaps your client
would like to revise his statement.
Hey.
Try this.
How you doing?
Good. Are you kidding?
That was amazing.
Can we do it again?
Lisbon. My office. Now.
Mr. Ridley and his lawyer
have made some serious claims
against you two.
They're only serious if they're true.
Are they?
No.
- No.
- So, you didn't threaten to kill Ridley?
And you didn't stage the death
of his associate?
No, of course not.
All right.
Well, then I'm done with you.
- Okay.
- Not you, Lisbon.
Jane is a liar.
No need to deny it. I expect it of him.
But you're not a liar, Lisbon.
You're an honest, good person
with a long career ahead of you
and I don't wanna see you throw away
this new opportunity of yours.
So...
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
Is there any truth
to Ridley's accusations?
No.
Everything Jane said was true.
You had an update for me?
I do.
"Earlier today, FBI agents working
with Colombian authorities"
"searched a container ship
in San Marta."
"They found 30 women on board."
"Your sister, Amy, was one of them."
"We found her."
- There you are.
- Hey.
- Ready to go?
- I am so ready.
You won't believe the day
I've had.
Yeah?
Look, uh, about D.C.
I know it's a lot to take in
and I didn't mean to pressure you.
Yeah, you did.
Yeah, I did.
Maybe a little.
But it's your life
and I just wanna be a part of it.
I've made up my mind.
I'm gonna call Don tomorrow
and tell him I'll take the job.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
Wow.
Wow. I wish we were somewhere
more romantic
but what the hell?
Will you marry me?
What?
- What?
- Don't freak out.
Um, wow. Marry you?
- Um...
- I know. I know.
- You need time to think about it.
- Yeah. It's, it's a big decision.
It's huge.
There's no pressure, okay?
Okay.
You're a tough date.
Have you told Jane
that you're leaving yet?
No. No, not yet.
- He'll understand.
- Yeah.
All right.
- I'll be downstairs.
- All right.
How'd it go with Abbott?
Thanks.
We make a good team sometimes.
Yeah. We do.
You heading out?
Yeah.
I... I'll see you tomorrow?
I'll be here.
Good night.